Guide to the Henry Hale Bucher, Sr. and Louise Scott Bucher Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- General Correspondence, Series II
  - Circular letters from Buchers to supporters and friends
    - 5 letters, from College of Chinese Studies, Peking [Beijing] and the Philippines, 1940 - 1941 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - 11 letters, from Hartford, CT, from Kiungchow, Hainan, from Ventnor, NJ, 1946 - 1949 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - 8 letters, from New Jersey, from Bangkok, 1951,1952, 1955 - 1957 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 10 letters, from Petchaburi [Phetburi], Thailand, 1958 Aug - 1961 Apr (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 10 letters, from New Jersey on furlough; from Phetburi, 1961 Dec - 1963 Dec (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 10 letters, from Phetburi, 1964 Apr - 1967 Jul (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 13 letters, from Phetburi, from U.S., including regarding Rev. C.T. Tsai, 1967 Sep - 1985 May (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 25 letters, from Sante Fe, NM, 1985 Jun - 1987 Nov (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 10 letters, from Duarte, CA, 1994 - 1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Letters to/from friends and colleagues
    - Letters from Henry's former students at Bangkok Christian College, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Letters from Henry's former students at Bangkok Christian College; letters to/from Dr. Bercovitz, College of Chinese Studies colleagues, Ralph C. Wells and Margaret Frame of Presbyterian Mission, 1931, 1938 - 1941 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Including to/from Ralph C. Wells and E.E. Walline of Presbyterian Mission, C.T. Tsai of Church of Christ in China, Espiritu Cardenas of the Philippines, 1945 - 1949 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Including to/from Marshall Welles, students of the Buchers in Thailand, 1950 - 1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Including to/from John Weir and Theodore Romig of Presbyterian mission regarding work in Thailand, Brown, Kneedler, Curtis, Muller, and others, 1960 - 1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Including to/from colleagues and former students in Thailand, 1966 - 1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Including from former students and colleagues in China and Thailand, to Princeton Theological Seminary Class of 1934, 1984 - 1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Including to/from former students and colleagues in China and Thailand, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Including to/from former students and colleagues in China and Thailand, 1992 -1997 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Including to/from former students and colleagues in China and Thailand, and from Sam Wells, Boot black in Princeton, NJ, no date (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Letters of others
    - Including circular letters of other missionaries and descriptions of internment experience of Bucher family, 1939 - 1944, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Communications from Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church and from American Consulate regarding situation for missionaries in China and Philippines during war, return of Hainan missionaries requested by Gen. and Mme. Chiang Kai-shek, 1937 - 1946 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Writings & Notes of Buchers, Series III
  - Reports of Henry H. Bucher, Sr.
    - Personal reports from China, Philippines, Thailand, 1936-1937, 1941, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "Dear Diary" accounts of field work in Hainan and Thailand (many with typed transcripts), 1947-1949, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Personal reports and reports of work from Thailand, 1962 -1965 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Sermon notes of Henry H. Bucher, Sr.
    - Sermon Notes, 1951 Jan - 1951 Oct; circa 1951 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sermon Notes, 1952 Jan - 1954 Feb (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Sermon Notes, 1975 - 1981 Apr (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Sermon Notes, 1981 May - 1981 Jun (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Sermon Notes, 1981 Jun - 1981 Sep (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Sermon Notes, 1981 Oct - 1981 Nov (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Sermon Notes, 1981 Dec; circa 1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Sermon Notes, 1982 Jan - 1982 Feb (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Sermon Notes, 1982 Apr - 1983 May (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Sermon Notes, 1983 Jun - 1984 Jul (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Sermon Notes, circa 1984 - 1993 Sep (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Sermon Notes, No date (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Sermon Notes, No date (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Sermon Notes, No date (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Sermon Notes, No date (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Sermon Notes, No date (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Sermon Notes, No date (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Sermon Notes, No date (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Sermon Notes, No date (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Notebook of sermons/notes in Thai script and English (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Notebook of sermons/notes in Thai script and English, with enclosed articles, clippings (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Writings for publication by Henry H. Bucher, Sr.
    - "Christian Workcamp"; "Christmas Story"; "The Church in China - A Warning to Laymen in America"; "The Church in Hainan - A Challenge to Laymen in America"; "A Handbook for Presbyterian Men", 1950-1952, 1972, no date (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "How to Train Talent in the Church"; "How's Your Teaching Vocabulary"; "The Influence of National Missions on the Life of America", 1952, 1955,no date (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - "Learning with International People: An MCM Legacy"; "Old Wine in New Wineskins"; "Perpetuating Interest in Missions"; "Petchaburi in Historical Perspective", 1956, 1981, no date (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - "A Profile in Courage and Faith: A Very Great Chinese Gentleman, Rev. C. T. Ts'ai of Shanghai"; "Signs of Hope"; "Sunday School Lessons on Mission", 1952, 1980s, no date (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "Thailand Shepherd"; "Together in Thailand"; "What We Owe to Christian Missionaries"; "Who is my Neighbor?"; "Why Mission?"; "Young People and World Missions"; "Missionary Memories - Thailand", 1950, 1955, 1962, 1987, no date (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous short articles for Presbyterian magazines, 1950 - 1952 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous short articles for Department of Missionary Education, Presbyterian Church, 1951 - 1953, no date (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Book reviews, 1950 - 1955 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Autobiographical writings by Henry H. Bucher, Sr.
    - 6 typescript autobiographical essays, including "Highlights from the Wartime Memoirs of Henry H. Bucher, Sr.", 1980 - 1993, no date (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous notes and writings of Henry H. Bucher, Sr.
    - Regarding missions, Hainan, China, Thailand, trip to Asia, 1946-1948, 1968, 1985, 1997, no date (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Petchaburi in Historical Perspective, no date (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Poem written for farewell party from Presbyterian Missionary Education Department; updates and "musings" from later life, 1955,1990s (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Writings of Louise Scott Bucher
    - Personal report; autobiographical essays; "Christmas in Petburi Thailand"; "Christmas in Thailand", 1955, 1972, no date (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Collected Material, Series IV
  - Regarding China
    - Hainan Newsletters - American Presbyterian Mission, 1934, 1935, 1937, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      These published newsletters contain some brief articles by and notices about the Buchers.
    - Hainan Newsletters - American Presbyterian Mission, ca. 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Histories of Hainan mission: "The Isle of Palms: Sketches of Hainan"; "Fifty Years in Hainan: American Presbyterian Mission 1881-1931"; report of Hainan Synod, 1919, 1931, ca. 1947 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Histories of Hainan mission: "Hainan Revisited" by Frieda R. B. Manus; "The Presbyterian Mission on Hainan Island Under the Japanese, 1937-1941" by Kathleen Lodwick, 1985, 1987, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - 4 articles re. Hainan Island by M. M. Moninger, from Lingnan Science Journal, 1932 - 1934 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Souvenir booklet, postcards, map, and miscellaneous articles about Hainan, 1986 - 1987, no date (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Booklet: "It's Happening in Peiping" for distribution by Young People's Department of Board of Foreign Missions, Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.; handwritten notes: "The Overture on Concubinage"; map of China, 1932, 1948, no date (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous articles and newsletters related to Christianity in China, 1985 - 1997, no date (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Regarding Philippines and internment experience
    - Poem, prayer, articles, clippings concerning raid to liberate internment camp at Los Ba単os on February 23, 1945, 1989-1996, no date (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Tributes to individuals interned in Philippines, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Books related to Los Ba単os raid and internment camps: "The Los Ba単os Raid: The 11th Airborne Jumps at Dawn"; "Interrupted Lives: Four Women's Stories of Internment during World War II in the Philippines"; "How We Took It" (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Books related to Los Ba単os raid and internment camps: "Captive Community" "The Los Ba単os Prison Camp Raid"; "We Survived War's Crucible"; "Behind Barbed Wire and High Fences" (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Books related to Los Ba単os raid and internment camps:"Escape at Dawn"; "Deliverance at Los Ba単os"; "Land of the Morning" (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Regarding Thailand
    - Handwritten essays by Thai students, 1930-1931 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Booklets related to Christianity in Thailand, including "The Siam Outlook" (1934); "Guide to Christian Work in Thailand"; "Christianity in Thailand", 1934, ca. 1950s (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Reports, calendars, articles related to Christianity in Thailand, 1957 - 1961 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Articles, programs, newsletter, dissertation related to Christianity in Thailand, 1970-1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Notices regarding First Thai Presbyterian Church, Covina, CA; articles re. Thailand in general, 1960s - 1995 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Thai language booklets, hymns, tributes related to Christianity in Thailand (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper article re. Prince Mahidol, ca. 1971 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Articles copied and distributed by HHB (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Articles and clippings (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, Series V
  - Biographical documentation
    - Biographical sketches, ca. 1951, 1958, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Chronological sequence: regarding internment in Philippines, award of Asiatic-Pacific Campaign Ribbons to Henry and Louise, 1942 - 1945 May (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Chronological sequence: clippings regarding return of Bucher family to U.S. following internment, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Chronological sequence: including clippings, tributes from Thailand, departure from Hawthorne residence in Leesburg, FL, 1946 - 1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Chronological sequence: including 50th anniversary Los Ba単os reunion, notices from Westminster Gardens, Duarte, CA, 1992 - 1997 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Regarding Louise Scott Bucher: scrapbook from time at State Teachers College, East Radford, Virginia, 1930 (Box OV1)
    - Regarding Louise Scott Bucher: yearbook from Radford High School, clippings from wedding, documentation and tributes from time of her death, 1933, 1996, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Regarding death of Henry Hale Bucher, Sr.: programs and arrangements, conveyance of ashes to Thailand, 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Regarding death of Henry Hale Bucher, Sr.: condolence cards and communications, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Regarding Bucher children: clippings regarding wedding of Anna Louise, book: "Ocho Ocho: My Childhood in War-Torn Asia" by Anna Bucher Jones, 1954, 2012 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      For material related to Henry Hale Bucher, Jr. see YDSL Record Group No. 250, Henry Hale Bucher, Jr. Papers
    - Regarding Bucher children: clippings, documents relating to Priscilla and Scott, including diary from Dhodital hiking trip taken by Scott in 1958, 1956 -1984, no date (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Regarding Priscilla Jo Bucher, including regarding health issues, personal memorabilia, 1950-1964 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Regarding Priscilla Jo Bucher, including obituaries, statements from memorial service, 2013 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Regarding extended families, 1942 - 1987, no date (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Artifacts, diplomas, certificates
    - Louise Bucher: certificate from U.S. Department of Agriculture State Agricultural College, diploma from State Teachers College, East Radford, VA, Thai language document with photograph, 1920, 1930, no date (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Louise Bucher: Pi Gamma Mus certificate, Commonwealth of Virginia State Teachers Certificate, documentation for substitute teaching, 1929, 1930, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Henry Bucher: Chinese business cards, greeting cards sent to his wife, certificate from Westminster College, 1992, no date (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Henry Bucher: diploma from Princeton Theological Seminary, Thai language certificate, 1934, no date (Box OV1)
    - Henry Bucher: Princeton diploma, Certificate of Ordination, Certificate of Church Membership, citation of Henry and Louise from COEMAR, United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A., 1934, 1950, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Chinese cash; Philippines cash - Victory Series No. 66 from World War II era; small silk banner with photograph and Chinese calligraphy; woven textile scene of river and path with Chinese calligraphy, 1940s, no date (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Guest book from Phetburi, Thailand and Sante Fe, New Mexico, 1962 - 1968, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Guest book from Thailand and U.S., 1968 - 1995 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Large silk banner with photograph of staff of Hoihow Hospital, Hainan surrounded by signatures of Chinese staff (Box OV-D5)
  - Audio-Visual Materials
    - Photographs
      - Family
        - Henry Hale Bucher, Sr., 1929 -1997 (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Henry Hale Bucher, Sr.: oversize group photos from Princeton Theological Seminary, 1933 - 1934 (Box OV1)
        - Louise Scott Bucher, 1933 - 1990s (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Henry and Louise Bucher, 1933 - 1990s (Box 10, Folder 4)
        - Immediate Bucher family: parents with children, 1935 - 1940s (Box 10, Folder 5)
        - Immediate Bucher family: parents with children, home in Haddonfield, NJ, 1950s - 1960s (Box 10, Folder 6)
        - Immediate Bucher family: parents with children, 1970s - 1990s (Box 10, Folder 7)
        - Bucher children: Anna Louise, 1934 - 1980s (Box 10, Folder 8)
        - Bucher children: Henry, Jr., 1936 - 1980s (Box 10, Folder 9)
        - Bucher children: Priscilla Jo, 1937 - 1990s (Box 10, Folder 10)
        - Bucher children: George Scott, 1942 - 1960s (Box 10, Folder 11)
        - Bucher children: in groups, 1936 - 2008 (Box 10, Folder 12)
        - Extended Bucher and Scott families, 1933 - 1997 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Related to mission work
        - Siam [Thailand]: loose photos, 1929 - 1931 (Box 11, Folder 1)
          Photos taken during period when Henry was teaching at Bangkok Christian College.
        - Siam [Thailand]: photo album, 1929 - 1931 (Box 11, Folder 2)
        - China: Kiungchow, Hainan, 1930s -1940s (Box 11, Folder 3)
        - China: Hainan (from visit of friend to former mission areas), 1984 (Box 11, Folder 4)
        - China: Peiping [Beijing], Hong Kong, 1946, no date (Box 11, Folder 5)
        - China: group photos of passengers on U.S.S. General Gordon, on which Buchers returned from China, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - Philippines, 1940s (Box 11, Folder 6)
        - Thailand: photo album showing services in church, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 7)
        - Thailand: photo album "Christmas Eve at the International Church", 1962 (Box 11, Folder 8)
        - Thailand: contents of photo album "To Sir With Love from M.S. 5 Science Aroonpradit School Petburi", 1968 (Box 11, Folder 9)
        - Thailand: photo album "Petburi Farewell Party for Mrs. Louise Bucher"; mounted photos from farewell to Buchers, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 10)
        - Thailand: photo albums, including "New dormitory for boys at Aroonpradit in Petburi", no date (Box 12, Folder 1)
        - Thailand: loose photos: groups and scenes of church work, 1960s - 1972 (Box 12, Folder 2)
        - Thailand: oversize photos of Church of Christ in Thailand meetings and Thailand Congress on Evangelism, ca. 1960s (Box 13, Folder 1)
        - Thailand: loose photos: buildings and scenes, 1960s - 1972, no date (Box 12, Folder 3)
        - Thailand: loose photos: buildings and scenes, 1960s - 1972, no date (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Thailand: mounted set of photographs regarding work in Thailand, sent by co-worker Frieda Manus (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Events
        - Westminster College 50th reunion, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 5)
        - 60th wedding anniversary, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
        - Reunion of China missionaries at Columbia Theological Seminary, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 7)
        - Reunion commemorating 50th anniversary of Los Ba単os rescue by U.S. Airborne, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 8)
        - Louise Scott Bucher funeral and memorial services, 1996-1997 (Box 12, Folder 9)
        - Bucher family trip to Asia, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 10)
        - Henry H. Bucher, Sr. memorial service in Thailand, 1998 (Box 12)
    - Audio-video recordings
      - 4 VHS tapes: 60th wedding anniversary, memorial services for Louise Scott Bucher, memorial service for Henry H. Bucher, Sr., 1993, 1996 - 1998 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - 2 audiocassette tapes: China Missionary Reunion, opening address by Bishop K.H. Ting; Henry Bucher, Sr. "Stories of Los Ba単os 2 CDs: Oral history by Henry H. Bucher regarding World War II internment by Japanese, 1985, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - DVD: Video oral history by Henry H. Bucher, Sr. regarding family historic documents and internment and liberation experience during WWII. (2 copies), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - DVD: History Channel Special: "Rescue at Dawn - The Los Ba単os Raid", 2008 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - 3 78 RPM records: Gospel recordings in Hainanese: "The Resurrection of Christ", "Ye Must Be Born Again", "The Prodigal Son", 1947 (Box OV1)